[Love of the Divine Tree]
[Episode 24]
If you still consider me as your master,
promise me,
don't be held back by anything.
Be as free as a bird.
Master.
Ranran!
Ranran.
Master, Mr. Yu Tong, and Mr. Yu Chen
are all gone this morning.
Master left me a note
saying he's never coming back.
What?
Well...
-Mr. Zeng.
Mr. Zeng.
Where's Master?
Where has Master gone?
Your master
has urgent matters to attend to.
He has already left Mount Wester.
Before leaving, he entrusted me,
if you want to go home,
he has prepared travel expenses for you.
If you want to join other sects,
he has also written letters of recommendation.
Master said he had urgent matters to attend to.
Has he gone to seal the Spirit Spring?
Seal the Spirit Spring?
When did Master plan to do this?
Actually, last time in Puxin Village,
the Nine-Headed Kui'ao we encountered
took away the stele
for sealing the Spirit Spring.
Mr. Zeng,
is that true?
Yes.
Sealing the Spirit Spring is urgent.
He now urgently needs
to find the gate to the netherworld.
But I haven't returned the soul
to Master yet.
How can Master, with a part of his spiritual soul missing,
manage to
suppress the Spirit Spring alone?
He is Su Yishui.
He has his own ways.
Missing a strand of spiritual soul
only hinders his ascension
to godhood,
right?
Why do I feel like
Master is saying a final farewell?
I don't believe
he would leave us disciples behind
if he was really confident.
Mr. Zeng,
are you hiding something
from us?
Once you leave,
there's no turning back.
Don't you want to say goodbye to Ranran?
She has always been clever.
If she senses anything,
I'll have trouble getting away.
This matter is too dangerous.
I can't let Ranran get involved.
She's a girl
who has always loved freedom.
Tea Inscription Mountain is a good place.
Why don't you take her
to open a wine shop?
All the money of the Wester Sect
is stored in the rice container in the dining room.
Stiffly Su,
actually,
there might be other ways.
Let's figure it out together.
It doesn't necessarily have to be you.
Besides,
Ranran has already gone to find a way
to return your soul.
Just wait a little longer.
I have one last drop
of the Spirit Spring left.
I need to end this fate.
Senior Zeng,
I'll leave her in your care.
How could that be?
It's your master.
You know him best.
He's such a cold fish,
acting on every whim.
Perhaps,
after he seals the Spirit Spring,
he might just find a quiet place
to cultivate.
Anyway,
he has already arranged everything
for you all.
You,
go to Tea Inscription Mountain with me.
I don't want to go anywhere!
Master took me to plant trees on Mount Wester.
He said the place where we planted trees
would be my home.
Why didn't he keep his word?
Why did he have to leave?
Did he want to avoid me that much?
Ranran.
Ran...
Ranran,
don't be sad all by yourself.
Xi'er,
let her be alone for a while.
Ling Xiao,
who am I really?
What does Master take me for?
Can you tell me?
Ling Xiao,
have I entered your memories
again?
Then,
these are Master's memories?
It's Master.
There's no Reincarnation Tree on this mountain yet.
Was it
19 years ago?
Qingge is dead.
Why can you be alive in this world?
Young Master Yu.
I'm going to kill you
to avenge Qingge!
Qingge could never be the Demon's child.
The Demon's child is someone else.
Tell me,
for whom did Qingge
take on this false accusation?
Of course, she wasn't.
The real Demon's child is...
You can't say it.
It's you,
the ungrateful scumbag,
right?
You resented her for siding with me,
so you made her
bear this terrible accusation
for you.
Don't forget,
if there's still one person in this world
who cares whether you're alive,
it's your master,
Mu Qingge.
But you
killed her with your own hands.
Why did you have to compete with me?
If you hadn't done so,
she wouldn't have ended up dead.
Prince Ping's entire army has been wiped out.
You've lost.
I told you long ago
that you had no chance of winning.
And now, you've even
sacrificed Qingge's life!
She's not dead.
Her spiritual soul hasn't perished.
I won't let her dissipate.
Your Highness,
on Jade Peak of Sky Mountain,
there is a Reincarnation Tree.
If we can offer a Golden Core as a sacrifice,
we can bring her primordial spirit back to life.
Retrieve Qingge's spiritual soul.
I will help her raise from the dead.
No one else will take her away.
Do you think after she's resurrected,
she'll still want to see you?
The person she always loved is me.
Even if it's to bring Qingge's spiritual soul back to life,
I should be the one to protect it!
What gives you the right to make decisions on your own
and trap her?
You're not worthy.
You must have known my identity
earlier.
Yet you deliberately used Qingge to provoke me,
didn't you?
You knew
only she could stop me.
You included her in your schemes.
What kind of love is that?
You and I are the same.
We're both the ones she shouldn't be close to
in her reincarnation.
Turns out Master and Young Master Yu
had such a history.
I've long known
that Master deeply loves Grandmaster,
but after I saw it with my own eyes,
why do I
still feel so painful?
Master has already brought back
the Reincarnation Tree.
There are two Reincarnation Fruits on the tree.
Could one of them be me?
Master!
Master, are you hurting?
When will Master be able to return?
The Reincarnation Tree defies the heavens.
It will take 18 years for her to be back to life.
You're severely injured.
You need to go into seclusion to save your life.
During these 18 years,
if anything happens,
how will you protect her?
I have my own ways.
Why are you extracting your own spiritual soul?
After this, I will seclude myself and lose all five senses.
This part of my spiritual soul
can accompany her.
This is Ling Xiao.
Master gave Ling Xiao to Master Mu.
If Master had Ling Xiao stay
in order to protect Mu Qingge,
why is it with me?
Could I be...
No.
This can't be.
How is this possible?
There must be a hidden chamber here.
Ling Xiao,
help me.
If it's really as I thought,
in my body
is Master's Golden Core.
My spiritual power is connected to Master's.
I should be able to open his hidden chamber.
He kept all the dried longan
I made for Master.
And the pastries I made for him.
The wine I made.
The sect rules Master made me copy as punishment.
Master actually kept all these little things about me
here in this place.
Why are there
so many Sanity Spells here?
I haven't given him
the dried longan I made last time.
Guardian never likes dried longan.
Then I'll leave it on the table.
If Master wants to have some,
he can take it anytime.
Sovereigns of the Wester Sect,
Mu Qingge,
Xue Ranran.
So I am the demoness
everyone talks about,
Mu Qingge, Sovereign of the Wester Sect.
The person Master has been waiting for
is me.
♫Devoting one's life despite knowing it can't be♫
You don't remember anything?
Senior!
♫Coming to the abyss despite knowing retreat is possible♫
What gives you the right to make a scene in my place?
Master,
♫Who says the world is full of wrongs?♫
you're so nice.
♫I seize the Way and choose heaven♫
Once you recall everything,
♫It won't be a waste of my life to burn until I wither♫
you won't forgive me.
Weird.
How did I suddenly
enter Master's Water Mirror?
♫There's no need to discuss right or wrong♫
♫I can sacrifice my life♫
Master, who do you
take me for?
♫All rules can be dismantled♫
Naturally, it's the person
♫Die in this world♫
I've been thinking about for 19 years.
♫The masses spread rumors that are hard to swallow♫
The person I love is clearly right in front of me,
♫I haven't said anything yet, my heart is clear♫
but I can't get her.
♫I still don't regret it; I'll pay for it all my life♫
Mu Qingge,
is this the only way for us
to live our lives in this life?
♫You know my heart, won't go against my wishes♫
♫Don't speak of redressing injustices♫
Master, look carefully
who you kissed!
♫Don't let others pity me♫
Of course, it has always been you!
♫Try your best to forget me♫
Liar.
♫I'll go through hardships and never break down♫
All these years, you've confined yourself,
keeping me in the dark so painfully.
♫I vow to fight against darkness♫
But why
♫Love punishes me a thousand times, yet a merciful heart pardons me♫
did you push me away like this,
given the fact that the person you've been waiting for is me?
♫No pain, no resentment♫
♫Devoting one's life despite knowing it can't be♫
Divine Tree.
♫Coming to the abyss despite knowing retreat is possible♫
I, Su Yishui, hereby take a soul oath.
From today,
I'll join your sect,
♫I'll go through hardships and never break down♫
focus on cultivation,
and never betray you.
Good boy.
♫I vow to fight against darkness♫
The soul oath is completed.
♫Love punishes me a thousand times, yet a merciful heart pardons me♫
♫Only love is the unbreakable spell♫
Master!
Mu Qingge!
♫No need to feel surprised people in the world don't know how to break it♫
No!
♫Sealing your lips, never to speak again♫
I will save you.
I will definitely save you!
♫Even if I were to leap into the abyss♫
♫If you are safe, I would embrace death without a second thought♫
The Qingming Sword has chosen me as its master.
I can actually remember some memories
of my past life.
But why do I
still have a shallow understanding?
Mr. Zeng,
the Qingming Sword has chosen me as its master.
I found this
in Master's room.
Master.
Mr. Zeng,
please don't be like this.
If other fellow disciples see you doing this,
they will be frightened.
I just want to know the truth.
Since you've already guessed,
I can't hide it from you anymore.
So I don't remember anything
because of the Soul-Devouring Lock inside my body.
Master has helped me stabilize my heart
all because of this.
All these years,
he has hoped I would avoid all dangers
and live this life peacefully.
Although I haven't recovered
all my memories,
I know
that neither the former Mu Qingge
nor the current Xue Ranran
wants
him to bear everything alone.
Can you tell me now
where Master has gone?
I really don't know.
All I know is
he was going to find the Xuantian Teachings.
But he never told me
where it is.
Then why didn't he take you with him?
Because...
Mr. Zeng,
since you consider me your master in my previous life,
please answer me truthfully.
Because this time,
there's no turning back.
What?
Back then,
you asked him to seal the Spirit Spring
because you anticipated that he
had reached the peak of Nascent Soul.
One step further,
he could enter the Transcendence Stage.
Then he could use all his power
to seal the Spirit Spring.
But to save you,
he sacrificed half of his core
and a strand of his spiritual soul.
So he couldn't reach the Transcendence Stage.
He can only use his own body
as a spiritual key
to seal the Spirit Spring.
If I find a way
to return Ling Xiao to him,
perhaps he
won't have to die.
Why couldn't he wait for me?
All these years,
he's practiced Ice Lotus Technique
to maintain his cultivation.
The Ice Lotus Technique
is cultivated based on the Unfeeling Mantra.
But his feelings for you...
So,
the Ice Lotus Technique is gradually dissipating.
If he waited any longer,
I'm afraid he wouldn't be able
to suppress the Spirit Spring in the bottle anymore.
'Be as free as a bird,' well said.
He's risking his life to seal the Spirit Spring,
yet he told me to start a new life.
Idiot.
Master Liang's sound transmission talisman.
According to Master Liang,
he has found a way
to return the spiritual soul.
It's also recorded in the Xuantian Teachings.
But where is it?
[Consonance Palace]
I'm Mu Qingge.
Consonance Palace, heed my command.
About what Su Yishui
searched for,
read,
and found out here,
show me everything!
Su Yu
came and took away the Xuantian Teachings.
Master must have gone to the imperial palace.
Master went to the capital
to retrieve the Xuantian Teachings.
I'll set off to find him right away.
I'll help him find a way
to return his spiritual soul.
The journey ahead is likely to be extremely perilous.
Since you've decided to go,
I'll go with you.
No need, Mr. Zeng.
If I miss Master
who returns early,
please make sure to keep him here for me.
Ranran.
We'll go with you.
He's our master too.
We can't possibly join another sect.
Master's affairs
are Wester Sect's affairs.
The capital is just ahead.
But the capital is so big.
Where should we look for Master?
I have a way.
Vermilion Bird.
You...
You've made it your spiritual beast?
No,
I haven't exchanged a soul contract with it.
If it wants to leave one day,
it can just do as it wants.
Found it.
How did you find this place?
[Private mansion, the capital]
Vermilion Bird led us here.
Let's cut to the chase.
Where's Master?
We're looking for him too.
We've lost contact with him.
Mr. Yu,
what's on earth going on?
That day,
we went to the capital.
It just rained heavily.
But it's strange.
How come it only rained over the capital?
It rains every day.
Every single day.
It's rained for over a month.
Sooner or later, the capital
will be flooded.
Rained for over a month?
It has rained since we
returned from Heavenly Meridian Mountain.
That day, the spiritual channel was damaged.
I remember there's a waterway in the moat
that leads directly to the imperial palace.
What exactly is Su Yu up to?
Guardian,
is there anything unusual?
That's a cultivator.
His Golden Core is gone.
There's something wrong
with the moat.
[Ru Yuan]
Young Master,
after so many years without news of you,
I
have finally seen you.
Rise, please.
Prince Ping fell long ago.
I'm not a young master anymore.
Even so,
back then, His Highness
secretly left behind a great fortune.
It would be enough for you to be extremely wealthy.
Why bother going up to the mountain
to suffer the cold and loneliness?
You've hidden your identity
and operated in the capital for many years.
You're also on good terms with many imperial family members.
Is there a way you can get me into the palace?
Guardian, why do you want to enter the palace?
Su Yu has something I need.
I didn't want to trouble you initially,
but today, outside the palace,
I saw he set up a Heavenly Formation at the four corners.
All spiritual power
will disappear once cultivators enter the palace.
I can't use magical techniques to get in or out.
This Su Yu.
He's become more cautious, hasn't he?
In recent years,
the Crown Prince has changed greatly from before.
These past few years,
he has extensively recruited
a group of unique scattered cultivators from the Heavenly
and established an Exotic Pavilion.
Around him,
there are talented cultivators from the Exotic Pavilion
protecting him.
Apart from these cultivators,
no one else can enter or leave the palace.
I've also heard something else.
His Majesty doesn't attend to state affairs.
The Crown Prince has been acting as a regent all along.
But strangely,
informants in the palace have leaked news
that His Majesty intends to depose the Crown Prince.
However, given the Third Prince's abilities,
he's clearly not as good as Su Yu,
and he can't be up to the task.
The remaining imperial heirs are all young.
I don't know why Su Yu
has become suspicious in His Majesty's eyes.
Su Yu isn't that good,
but his younger brothers
are even more incompetent.
However,
has he asked these cultivators from the Exotic Pavilion
to do
anything special?
Young Master,
why do you ask?
Today, as I passed through the capital,
I saw a cultivator
who had drowned in the moat.
His Golden Core is gone.
The previous cultivators who died there
also had their Golden Cores missing.
What does Su Yu want
with so many Golden Cores?
I don't know either.
But the manager of the Exotic Pavilion,
called Feng,
has expanded the small Inquiry Pond
in the palace
into a large lake.
I've also heard
that the day after tomorrow,
a new group of extraordinary talents
will enter the palace.
If you have no other way,
perhaps you could blend in among them.
It is
indeed a way.
But Guardian,
why bother getting involved in these matters?
Clearly, there is
a good life of luxury
waiting for you here.
I've watched you grow up since you were little.
Have you
lost your former vision?
I'm from the Exotic Pavilion.
Do I still need to be verified?
[Bao Ming, Immortal Master of the Exotic Pavilion]
No need, no need.
Please.
Guardian, look.
Guardian.
This Smokescreen won't last more than two days.
Are you sure it's safe?
If I don't come out in two days,
you should return to Mount Wester
and evacuate the disciples immediately.
Guardian.
Next one.
Who goes there?
I am Bao Ming from Mount Suiyun.
I've been invited here.
Previously,
at Wangxiang Pass, I saw
that human corpses merged with fish.
I was wondering
if in this world,
there really exists the Seven Evil Transformation Spell,
such a miraculous spell.
Now that I've met you,
I fully believe it really exists.
I believe His Highness will be delighted
to have such a rare talent as you.
His Highness has been waiting for you for a long time.
Please.
Within a month, cultivators with Golden Cores
fell into the moat and drowned one after another.
Moreover,
they all lost their Golden Cores.
Could it be that
there's a demon in the moat
specifically eating Golden Cores?
The moat's waterway
flows through the Eastern Palace's Inquiry Pond.
Guardian said
that these strange occurrences
had something to do
with Su Yu.
Young Master Yu?
He killed people and took away Golden Cores.
But he seems so kind and friendly,
caring for the people.
Someone who can become the Crown Prince
is certainly not a simple character.
The Eastern Palace has set up a special formation
to suppress Heavenly spiritual power.
I wonder
how Guardian is doing now.
Let's get into the palace to help Master.
Right.
The Eastern Palace's security is absolutely watertight.
It's not easy to get in.
If we cause a commotion,
it might further implicate Guardian.
So what should we do now?
Don't worry.
We can't get in,
but Vermilion Bird can.
For now, we can only first find out
about Master's situation
and then plan our next move.
Get out!
Spiritual medicine is completely useless!
You're all a bunch of useless trash!
The wound on her face hasn't healed yet.
She's done so many bad things.
It's her own fault.
Your Highness,
the area around Huixiang Spring
has been cleared for you.
They say that the spring
has miraculous effects on healing wounds.
Vermilion Bird,
go look for Master elsewhere.
Hurry!
Has the immortal master arrived?
What's on earth in the water?
They even used such a powerful formation
to suppress it.
Sir,
this way, please.
His Highness is just ahead.
Su Yu is a man of many schemes.
Once he gets his hooks into you,
it's hard to break free.
I need to change my identity.
Finding the Xuantian Teachings is urgent.
Guards.
Yes.
We've found him, Lord Feng.
Lord Feng,
look.
It's not him.
Not him?
Well...
Why is he Master Liu?
[Su Yu's Study, Eastern Palace]
Vermilion Bird,
quickly follow and see.
Don't get caught.
The scent of a thousand-year-old red pine.
This fragrance doesn't dissipate easily.
The books that were once stored here
must still have traces of the woody scent.
I can track its whereabouts by the smell.
How come
it is in Inquiry Pond?
I wrote a letter to invite you here openly,
yet you chose to disguise yourself
and sneak in.
Indeed,
an illegitimate born of a dancer
can never be presentable.
You used Ranran's identity
to lure me here.
What exactly are you up to?
Also,
cultivators in the capital frequently fell into the moat
and lost their Golden Cores.
Is it because of
what you've suppressed in the pond?
What exactly are you trying to do?
How smart
you are.
You spotted the secret in the water at a glance.
However,
you've never seemed to like
meddling in others' affairs.
Why?
Surely it can't be
that you've become Wester Sect's sovereign
and changed your nature, right?
As for Ranran...
Now that I know
her true identity,
I will naturally restore her title
as Madam Battle
and return everything that belongs to her.
I'll let her stay by my side
just like before.
Absolutely impossible.
She is now Xue Ranran.
She has her own life.
Ridiculous.
What gives you the right
to keep Ranran who knows nothing
by your side?
Who was it that harmed her in the first place?
Have you forgotten
what you've done?
She
is the only one in my heart
who can be the Crown Princess.
In this world,
I am the one who truly loves her
and protects her.
I may not be qualified,
but you're even less so.
It seems Su Yishui
doesn't like what others gifted you.
It's a pity about this hairpin.
Although it's not valuable,
it was chosen
with great care.
With your help,
how can we fail in our grand course?
Qingge,
Su Yishui is your disciple.
Why have you
never considered assisting him?
Qingge, be careful!
Back then, you repeatedly used her,
instigating conflict between me and her,
to fulfill your own purposes.
To provoke me,
you didn't hesitate to use her as a pawn.
The love you speak of,
to you,
is nothing but an ornament
beyond power and fame.
If you're asked to trade what you've gained today
for Ranran's love,
will you do it?
How do you know I won't?
If you have the guts, don't hesitate.
The person who can stay by Ranran's side
should be someone
who loves her wholeheartedly.
But you
are simply not worthy.
Shut up!
No one can stop me from getting what I want!
He can't use his spiritual power.
Capture him for me!
He stole Master Liu's Spiritual Power Token.
Don't let him get out of the Eastern Palace.
Master!
Guardian!
Master! Master!
Why are you all here?
Yu Tong, Yu Chen,
quickly take these four away.
Return to Mount Wester immediately. Don't come to find me.
Master!
I've already set up different formations against you.
What you have in your hand
is just a low-level token.
You can't use much spiritual power.
You can't escape now.
Everyone, come on!
This is bad!
The thing in the water can't be suppressed anymore!
Look, what's happening to this water?
Something's not right here.
Quick, let's go! Let's go!
What's going on?
There seems to be uncontrollable malevolent energy in this water.
Your Highness,
the thing in Inquiry Pond can't be suppressed anymore!
In less than 15 minutes,
the capital will be flooded!
What?
Suppress it!
Master!
[Inquiry Pond]
There's so much resentment in the water.
I just discovered that
the Xuantian Teachings is underwater,
but I don't know its exact location.
Dragon.
Su Yu dares to keep a dragon in the palace.
What is he up to?
[Xuantian Teachings]
Su Yu used the Xuantian Teachings
to suppress the dragon.
Could it be...
Master.
Could it be
the dragon egg that Meng Zhang lost?
I never expected to encounter it here.
The soul oath will activate
upon meeting.
If the oath is not fulfilled immediately,
it'll be considered a breach.
It seems now,
whether to honor the soul oath
or obtain the Xuantian Teachings,
I must first tame this Green Dragon.
But its malevolent energy is hard to control right now.
If it's rashly taken out of the palace
without being suppressed,
the entire capital will suffer.
I've come up with an idea.
Spirit-Controlling Soul Separation.
Where is he?
He's not found in the water!
He entered Inquiry Pond and disappeared.
Could he ruin
our grand plan?
Your Highness, rest assured.
In such a short time,
he can't get out.
He must still be somewhere in the palace.
Search!
Yes!
Even if I have to force my way into the Eastern Palace,
I will rescue Guardian!
Wait.
Guardian instructed
to take them away first.
Now those from the Eastern Palace
must be searching for us everywhere.
If we're caught,
Guardian will be in an even worse situation.
Are we just going to do nothing?
Stop arguing.
To save Master,
the formation suppressing spiritual power in the Eastern Palace
is the biggest obstacle.
As long as we break the formation,
it should not be difficult
for Master to escape.
But the Eastern Palace is impregnable.
How can we get in?
Old tricks can still work.
We can use Master's trick of substitution
one more time.
Substitution?
Who are you going to substitute for?
Mu Qingge in the palace.